OLAMIJI BADMOS

Address: Federal Institute of Industrial Research Oshodi, Lagos.

Phone Number: +234 809 870 2835
Email: badmosolamiji@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/olamijibadmos
GitHub: https://github.com/thebadmos

Portfolio: https://olamijibadmos.herokuapp.com

CAREER SUMMARY

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Translating designs to front-end code and determining developer requirements

Respected Front-end web developer with 3+- years of experience in collaborating with creative and development teams on the execution of ideas and projects.

Key Competences

- Promoting and communicating new ideas • Creating process improvements • Instituting new technologies
- Frameworks
- Browser developer tools

- Writing maintainable cross-browser code
- Estimating time and costs for projects •

Ensuring code is scalable and responsive •

Cross browser development

• Responsive/Mobile design

EDUCATION DATE Babcock University, Ilisan, Ogun State. 2018 Bachelor Degree (**BSc**) in Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

Stutern Graduate Accelerator Program for Software Engineering 2020 Udemy MERN stack 2021 Coursera Front End Web Development with React 2021

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES(Proficient) Level HTML Tools: HTML5 Boilerplate

Intermediate CSS Tools: Bootstrap, Sass, Material UI Intermediate JavaScript Framework: ReactJs, JavaScript, MongoDb, ExpressJs, NodeJs Intermediate Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, Power Point, Access and Outlook)

Platforms (Window & MACOS)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Truckka Logistics Limited, Maryland, Lagos State

Projects Technology Officer April 2021 – August 2021 Translate designs to front-end code, estimate project time and costs, determine developer requirements and specifications, and work with a cross-functional team to define and develop product roadmaps. *Responsibilities*:

- Increasing scalability, maintainability, and responsiveness of cross-browser code by 47%. Creating and implementing a custom CSS grid system, with CSS media queries for mobile responsiveness
- Creating and maintaining the front-end standards document and oversaw production of Javascript,

HTML, and CSS.

- Developing fully functional responsive prototypes based on Business Requirements using HTML/HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Consulting and documenting UI best practices and code standards.
- Leveraging responsive web frameworks to consistently complete product deliverables ahead of schedule Created 2 website within 3 months ahead the project deadlines
- Maintaining brand standards under company guidelines.

Stutern Accelerator Program, Lagos State

Software Developer Intern Dec 2019 – Nov 2020 Updated and streamlined existing code to improve site performance for the company.

Responsibilities:

- Led software programming and implementation projects, using a variety of programming languages, such as JavaScript, ReactJs and HTML & Css.
- Wrote support documentation and provided training to internal and external users.
- Exposed to a breadth of new and challenging tasks that contributed to the web application Collaborated in a team of 5 Software Engineers that engaged in a variety of tasks
- Developed and maintained various web applications including an e-commerce web app, inventory manager app.
- Formulated optimal solutions through extensive research into relevant technologies, existing code base, and open source libraries.

(NYSC) Bureau of Information Technology Dec 2019 – Nov 2020 Software Developer Intern *Responsibilities:*

- Tested, debugged, and verified various software releases and platforms for quality assurance purposes.
- Consulted with clients regularly, projects, proposals and technical issues that arise during the development process.
- Consulted with Supported team computer needs with skilled installation of devices, cables and software. Answered user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems.

Information Engineering Technology Limited, Lagos Feb 2017 – Aug 2017 **Software Developer Intern** *Responsibilities:*

- Produced clean, error-free code to meet an aggressive timeline.
- Adapted existing software to new purposes, improving performance and including new functionality. Composed documentation to improve knowledge sharing and on- boarding process. Measured project progress against performance goals by documenting project specifications from start to completion.

INTEREST

Writing, Travelling and Research